TAN LI HAU Frontend Engineer

Ihtan93@gmail.com | +65 8279 6285 https://github.com/tanhauhau https://sg.linkedin.com/in/lihautan https://lihautan.com

PROFILE

I love solving challenging problems and take pride in building solutions with excellent quality. At work, I lead the web frontend platform team, which provides technical solutions, building frameworks and infrastructures to the rest of the web frontend team. Outside of work, I participated in open source. I am one of the core maintainers of the Svelte framework.

I love learning and I am able to apply what I have learned quickly. In university, I took an extra Minor in Business to broaden my financial knowledge. In my previous position, I was put into a new team to work on a new project with an entire new Tech stack. I learned React on-the-job, and delivered the product with quality by the deadline.

For leisure, I enjoy running and traveling. I have participated in half marathons since 2017 as part of my new year resolution. I travel to different countries every year for vacation as well as attending Javascript conferences.

EXPERIENCE

Shopee, Sea Limited Aug 2017 – Present

Web Frontend Platform Team Lead

Sea Limited is a leading global consumer internet company founded in Singapore.

My key responsibilities are:

- Develop performant and optimized web applications
- Build and upgrade internal frameworks and tools to improve developer experience and efficiency
- Advocate new technologies and best practices within the team

My key contributions are:

- Developed micro-frontends architecture on-top of existing monolithic single-page application to allow each feature teams to develop, build, and deploy applications independently
- Built and maintained Web Frontend Release Platform to allow pre-build web application and release management, speed up release processes
- Built a rich set of development tools to improve developer experience (DX), such as chrome extension, cli tools, custom CI pipeline
- Set up performance metrics monitoring platform
- Upgraded React 16 and migrated legacy code
- Optimized webpack bundle size to reduce load time

Technology used:

• React, TypeScript, webpack, Playwright, monorepo, micro frontend

NINJAVAN June 2016 – Aug 2017 Software Engineer

Ninja Van is Southeast Asia's fastest growing last-mile logistics company.

My key responsibilities are:

• Write excellent quality frontend and backend code

- Plan and develop features, fix bugs and deploy applications through continuous integration to test and production environments
- Engage in code reviews with colleagues

My key contributions are:

- Lead and developed a React powered consumer web application within 2 months from scratch.
- Set up Jest unit test and Continuous Integration for React application
- Lead in implementing style guide on Angular powered frontend portal. Built a suite of reusable Angular directives and a set of Sass utility functions.

Technology used:

 AngularJS, React, React Native, Redux, Redux Saga, Java Play Framework, Git, Bamboo, webpack, Jest

ACTIVATE INTERACTIVE

2015 - 2016

Intern & Part Time

Activate Interactive is a software company that develops creative and impactful products.

My key contributions are:

 Built mobile apps using Titanium SDK for a nationalwide campaign for Health Promotion Board Singapore

Technology used:

• Titanium SDK, JavaScript

SCHOOL OF COMPUTER ENGINEERING

2013 - 2014

Student Assistant

My key contributions are:

- Built JavaScript d3.js driven, web-based data visualization tools, helped gain insights in analyzing network flow data.
- Co-authored the paper: Chonho Lee, Liu Yi, Li-Hau Tan, Weihan Goh, Bu-Sung Lee and Chai-Kiat Yeo, "A Wavelet Entropy-based Change Point Detection on Network Traffic: A Case Study of Heartbleed Vulnerability", Enterprise Security 2014, CloudCom
- Built Django powered backend, jQuery powered frontend, web portal for the research titled, "User and Domain Driven Data Analytics as a Service Framework"

Technology used:

• d3.js, jQuery, Python, Django

PROJECT

NTU Timetable Android APP

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.lhtan.ntutimetable

- Developed over a summer holiday
- Fetch and parse HTML from NTU Student Portal. Fetch Public Holiday from Ministry of Manpower. Calculate and store timetable data in local database. Show and notify user about the next class to attend.
- 4.2 stars with 52 reviewers

Technology used:

Android, Java

MULTI-DISCIPLINARY PROJECT

- Built a robotic system that can autonomously explore and traverse unknown areas
- Chief Arduino Engineer, designed obstacle detection and robot alignment algorithm

Technology used:

Arduino, Python

EDUCATION

2012-2016
NANYANG TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY
B.Eng in Computer Engineering, Minor in Business

SKILLS

JavaScript, React, Svelte, micro frontends, webpack, monorepo

OPEN SOURCE

Contributed in open source projects:

- Svelte core maintainer
- Babel contributor

Spoke at various conferences:

- CityJS 2020 Looking into the Svelte Compiler
- Svelte Society Day 2020 The Svelte compiler
- Front Conference 2022 Build your own Svelte
- CityJS 2022 Introduction to SvelteKit
- CityJS 2023 I built my wedding site with SvelteKit
- 稀土掘金开发者大会2023 (XDC 2023) 前端框架第二春:编译型框架教会了我们什么?(The new wave of frameworks: what can we learn from compiler-based frameworks?)

PUBLICATION

Real-World Svelte - Published by Packt Publishing